Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have a fun and scary dialogue.
今天我们有一个既有趣又吓人的对话。
That's right.
没错。
This lesson is full of language you can use to talk about being scared.
这节课充满了可以用来谈论害怕的语言。
Alright, so we're gonna be looking at a scary lesson today and we have nothing to preview
好的，所以今天我们要看一个吓人的课程，而且我们没什么要预习的。
so let's listen to this dialogue and see why everyone is so scared.
所以让我们听听这个对话，看看为什么大家都这么害怕。
Hey, why are we at this scary looking mansion?
嘿，我们为什么在这栋看起来很吓人的豪宅前？
It's like ultra spooky.
它超级阴森。
I told you already Shabby.
我已经告诉过你了，Shabby。
The owner of the house says there's a ghost haunting his house.
房主说他的房子里有鬼魂出没。
So we have to go in and investigate.
所以我们得进去调查。
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这样。
Come on guys, stop being such cowards.
拜托，伙计们，别这么胆小。
It's a mystery and an adventure.
这是个谜团，也是一场冒险。
This place gives me the creeps.
这地方让我毛骨悚然。
Seriously guys, let's get out of here.
说真的，伙计们，我们离开这儿吧。
I'm getting goosebumps just being here.
我光是待在这儿就起鸡皮疙瘩了。
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
Shabby是个胆小鬼。
That laugh came from this room.
那个笑声是从这个房间传来的。
Let's go and check it out.
我们进去看看吧。
Look, a ghost!
看，有鬼！
Run!
快跑！
Well, that sounds really scary but actually it kind of reminds me of another TV show.
嗯，那听起来确实很吓人，但实际上它让我想起了另一个电视节目。
Very similar to another TV show but it's different.
和另一个电视节目非常相似，但又不完全一样。
Okay, but some interesting language that you can use to talk about things that are scary
好的，但有一些有趣的语言可以用来谈论吓人的事情。
so why don't we look at that now in Language Takeaway.
所以我们不如在“语言要点”环节来看看。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So let's start with the very first line of our dialogue.
那么我们从对话的第一行开始。
Shabby described the mansion to be ultra spooky.
Shabby形容这栋豪宅是“ultra spooky”。
It's ultra spooky.
它超级阴森。
Spooky.
阴森的。
So, okay, we've got two interesting words here, ultra and spooky.
所以，这里有两个有趣的词，“ultra”和“spooky”。
Now spooky is scary, right?
“Spooky”就是吓人的，对吧？
It's a little bit scary.
它有点吓人。
It maybe makes you feel a little bit uncomfortable or maybe it makes you feel a little bit scared.
它可能让你感到有点不舒服，或者让你有点害怕。
Okay, so not very scared.
好的，所以不是非常害怕。
Not super scared.
不是超级害怕。
But ultra spooky.
但是超级阴森。
So ultra is another way of saying super or very or really spooky.
所以“ultra”是“super”或“very”或“really spooky”的另一种说法。
So if it's ultra spooky then it's...
所以如果它“ultra spooky”，那就是……
Very scary.
非常吓人。
Okay.
好的。
All right, so our next word.
好了，接下来是我们的下一个词。
They said that in the house there is a ghost haunting the house.
他们说那房子里有个鬼魂在作祟。
Okay, there is a ghost haunting his house.
好的，有个鬼魂在他的房子里作祟。
Okay, so the verb to haunt.
好的，所以动词是“haunt”。
Okay, to haunt.
好的，“haunt”。
So the ghost is coming to the house frequently and not letting them live in peace.
所以这个鬼魂经常来这房子，不让他们安宁地生活。
When a ghost haunts something, it visits it often and scares it.
当鬼魂作祟时，它经常造访并吓唬人。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, they were all afraid and they didn't want to go in and so Wilma called everyone
现在，他们都很害怕，不想进去，于是Wilma叫大家
cowards.
懦夫。
Stop being such cowards.
别这么懦弱了。
Cowards.
懦夫。
So, a coward.
所以，“coward”。
A coward is a person that's not brave.
“coward”是指不勇敢的人。
A person who's scared of everything.
一个什么都怕的人。
Exactly.
没错。
So, they were being cowards.
所以，他们当时表现得很懦弱。
They were afraid so that's why they didn't want to go in.
他们害怕，所以不想进去。
Well, speaking of being afraid, Shabby said, I'm getting goose bumps.
说到害怕，Shabby说：“我起鸡皮疙瘩了。”
Goose bumps.
鸡皮疙瘩。
To get goose bumps.
起鸡皮疙瘩。
All right, to get goose bumps.
好的，起鸡皮疙瘩。
Now, goose bumps, it may sound a little bit strange but it's very easy when you're scared
现在，“goose bumps”听起来可能有点奇怪，但很容易理解：当你害怕时
or maybe you're cold, the skin on your arms or on your back, it gets a little bit bumpy.
或者觉得冷，你手臂或背上的皮肤会变得有点凹凸不平。
So your skin looks like chicken skin.
所以你的皮肤看起来像鸡皮。
Exactly, chicken skin and that's actually how we call it in Spanish, chicken skin but
没错，鸡皮，在西班牙语里我们就是这么叫的，但这里是“goose bumps”，所以我觉得挺相似的。
this is goose bumps so I guess it's kind of similar.
鹅。
A goose.
是的，同一个意思。
Yeah, same idea.
鸡皮疙瘩。
Goose bumps.
好的，最后，Scruffy说：“Shabby是个胆小鬼。”
All right and finally, Scruffy said, Shabby is a scaredy cat.
胆小鬼。
A scaredy cat.
你是个胆小鬼。
You're a scaredy cat.
嗯，“scaredy cat”其实不是猫，对吧？
Well, a scaredy cat is not really a cat, right?
不，不，不。
No, no, no.
It's a person who's afraid of everything.
这是一个什么都害怕的人。
Okay.
好的。
Similar to a coward.
类似于懦夫。
But more informal.
但更随意一些。
Much more informal.
非常随意。
So somebody is a scaredy cat and I think even a little bit more juvenile.
所以有人是胆小鬼，我觉得甚至更幼稚一点。
As adults.
作为成年人。
So children use it.
所以孩子们会用这个词。
Yeah, as adults, you wouldn't say he's a scaredy cat.
是的，作为成年人，你不会说他是胆小鬼。
All right, great.
好的，很棒。
So some interesting scary language.
所以是一些有趣的恐怖语言。
I think we need to hear it one more time slowed down in the dialogue.
我觉得我们需要再听一遍对话中慢速的版本。
Eddie, why are we at this scary looking mansion?
埃迪，我们为什么在这座看起来很吓人的大宅子里？
It's like ultra spooky.
它超级阴森。
I told you already, Shabby.
我已经告诉过你了，沙比。
The owner of the house says there's a ghost haunting his house.
房主说他的房子里有鬼魂出没。
So we have to go in and investigate.
所以我们得进去调查。
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这样。
Come on, guys.
来吧，伙计们。
Stop being such cowards.
别这么懦弱了。
It's a mystery and an adventure.
这是个谜团和冒险。
This place gives me the creeps.
这地方让我毛骨悚然。
Seriously, guys.
说真的，伙计们。
Just get out of here.
赶紧离开这里吧。
I'm getting goosebumps just being here.
光是待在这里我就起鸡皮疙瘩了。
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
沙比是个胆小鬼。
That laugh came from this room.
那个笑声是从这个房间传来的。
Let's go and check it out.
我们进去看看。
Look, a ghost.
看，一个鬼魂。
Run.
快跑。
Okay, so now that we understand all the vocabulary we saw in language takeaway, why don't we
好的，既然我们理解了语言摘录中所有的词汇，不如
take a look at two phrases now in Fluency Builder.
来看看流利度提升中的两个短语。
Well, Shabby said we're at this scary looking mansion.
嗯，沙比说我们在这座看起来很吓人的大宅子里。
Scary looking mansion.
看起来很吓人的大宅子。
So a scary looking mansion.
所以是一座看起来很吓人的大宅子。
Okay, so the mansion looks scary.
好的，所以这座大宅子看起来很吓人。
All right, so a mansion is a big house, right?
好的，所以大宅子是大房子，对吧？
That looks very scary.
看起来非常吓人。
Now this is a really useful and helpful pattern you can use with English.
这是一个非常有用且实用的英语模式。
Something looking.
某物看起来……
So adjective looking.
看起来真够形容词的。
Right, so you can say good looking.
对，所以你可以说“好看”。
And there's lots of examples, so why don't we hear a few more now.
有很多例子，不如我们现在再听几个。
Example one.
例子一。
That guy is making me nervous.
那家伙让我紧张。
He's really creepy looking.
他看起来真吓人。
Example two.
例子二。
I saw the craziest looking house today.
我今天看到一栋最奇怪的房子。
It was built upside down.
它是倒着建的。
Example three.
例子三。
What a nice looking dog.
多好看的狗啊。
Can I pet him?
我能摸摸它吗？
All right, great examples, and now we know how we can combine looking with different
好的，很好的例子，现在我们知道如何把“looking”和不同的
adjectives.
形容词组合了。
For our next phrase, Shabby said this place gives me the creeps.
对于下一个短语，Shabby 说“这地方让我毛骨悚然”。
All right, gives me the creeps.
好的，“让我毛骨悚然”。
To give someone the creeps.
让某人毛骨悚然。
So if something gives you the creeps.
所以如果某物让你毛骨悚然。
It makes you feel uncomfortable and scared.
它会让你感到不舒服和害怕。
Maybe scared, maybe nervous.
也许是害怕，也许是紧张。
Okay, so why don't we give some examples.
好的，那我们举些例子吧。
I could say, hey Marco, see that guy over there?
我可以说，嘿 Marco，看到那边那个人了吗？
He keeps looking at me.
他一直在看我。
He's giving me the creeps.
他让我毛骨悚然。
Okay, or I can say clowns give me the creeps.
好的，或者我可以说小丑让我毛骨悚然。
Oh, that's right.
哦，没错。
You're afraid of clowns.
你害怕小丑。
I am afraid of clowns.
我害怕小丑。
They give me the creeps.
他们让我毛骨悚然。
All right, well, it's a really helpful, useful phrase to use when you're talking about being
好的，这是一个非常有用、实用的短语，当你谈论
afraid.
害怕时可以用。
Now why don't we listen to the dialogue one final time?
现在我们最后听一遍对话吧？
Eddie, why are we at this scary looking mansion?
Eddie，我们为什么在这栋看起来吓人的大宅子里？
It's like ultra spooky.
它超级阴森。
I told you already shabby.
我已经告诉过你了 Shabby。
The owner of the house says there's a ghost haunting his house.
房主说有个鬼魂在他的房子里作祟。
So we have to go in and investigate.
所以我们得进去调查。
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这样。
Come on guys, stop being such cowards.
拜托，伙计们，别这么胆小。
It's a mystery and an adventure.
这是个谜团和冒险。
This place gives me the creeps.
这地方让我毛骨悚然。
Seriously guys, let's get out of here.
说真的，伙计们，我们快离开这儿吧。
I'm getting goosebumps just being here.
光是待在这里我就起鸡皮疙瘩了。
Shabby is a scaredy cat.
沙比是个胆小鬼。
That laugh came from this room.
那笑声是从这个房间传来的。
Let's go and check it out.
我们过去看看吧。
Look, a ghost.
看，有鬼。
Run.
快跑。
Okay, so an interesting dialogue about ghosts and haunted houses.
好了，这是一段关于鬼魂和鬼屋的有趣对话。
So what do you think, Erica?
那么，艾丽卡，你怎么看？
Do you believe in ghosts?
你相信有鬼吗？
Have you ever seen a ghost?
你见过鬼吗？
No, I totally do not believe in ghosts.
不，我完全不相信有鬼。
But I understand that you disagree with me.
但我知道你不同意我的看法。
Well, I've experienced strange things, but I don't know if it was a ghost or an alien.
嗯，我经历过一些奇怪的事，但我不确定那是鬼还是外星人。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It could have been anything.
可能是任何东西。
An alien?
外星人？
An invisible alien.
一个隐形的外星人。
Okay.
好吧。
So what happened?
那发生了什么？
Well, once I was having dinner with my parents and we had a table and on top of the table,
嗯，有一次我和父母吃晚饭，我们有一张桌子，桌子上
there was a glass full of water.
放着一杯装满水的玻璃杯。
And all of a sudden it started to move across the table and then it started to spin while
突然它开始在桌子上移动，然后一边移动一边旋转。
it moved.
它移动的时候还在转。
And was there an earthquake or something happening?
当时是不是发生了地震之类的？
No, nothing.
不，什么都没有。
We were just, the only thing on the whole table that was moving was that.
我们只是，整张桌子上唯一在动的就是那个杯子。
And we all just kind of stared at the glass moving and we didn't know what to do.
我们都只是盯着那个移动的杯子，不知道该怎么办。
And then my mom started kind of giggling a nervous laugh and we really didn't know what
然后我妈妈开始有点紧张地咯咯笑，我们真的不知道
happened.
发生了什么。
Now, I understand that in Latin America, people are more superstitious.
我知道在拉丁美洲，人们更迷信。
They believe more in ghosts, right?
他们更相信鬼魂，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
In Latin America, people are very superstitious.
在拉丁美洲，人们非常迷信。
They believe in ghosts or in spirits or we have a lot of urban legends about, you know,
他们相信鬼魂或灵魂，我们有很多都市传说，比如
like a leprechaun that lives under a bridge or, you know, somebody's grandma that comes
桥下住着的小妖精，或者某人的奶奶回来
and haunts them or visits them at night and stuff like that.
闹鬼或晚上来看他们之类的。
So yeah, Latin American people are very superstitious in this sense.
所以是的，拉丁美洲人在这个意义上非常迷信。
Yeah, I think in Anglo countries, it's a little bit less common to say that you believe in
是啊，我觉得在英语国家，说自己相信
ghosts.
鬼魂。
Like maybe inside you, you think ghosts are true, but you wouldn't really tell people
比如你心里可能觉得鬼魂是真的，但不会真的告诉别人
that.
这一点。
I think the difference would be that you have a different type of superstition.
我觉得区别在于，你们有不同类型的迷信。
Like people are afraid of black cats or the floor or the number 13.
比如人们害怕黑猫、地板或者数字13。
Yeah, or opening your umbrella in a house.
是啊，或者在屋里打开雨伞。
Exactly.
没错。
So, because they consider it to be bad luck, but not because something like a ghost or
所以，因为他们认为这会带来坏运气，而不是因为像鬼魂或
an alien is going to come out and eat them.
外星人那样会出来吃掉他们。
So listeners, why don't you tell us what you think about ghosts?
所以听众们，为什么不告诉我们你们对鬼魂的看法呢？
Are people superstitious in your country?
你们国家的人迷信吗？
Do they believe in ghosts?
他们相信鬼魂吗？
Come to our website, EnglishPod.com and let us know and we'll see you guys there.
来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 告诉我们，我们会在那里等你们。
Well, thanks for downloading and goodbye!
好了，感谢下载，再见！